---
layout: post
title: LECTIO PRIMA
date:   2025-06-09
categories:
visible: false
author: Eugenio Pace
---

`This is LEsson one

```
---
questions:
  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The girl reads the book"
    words:
      - puella
      - legit
      - librum
      - arbor
      - ascendunt
    answer:
      - puella
      - librum
      - legit

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The sailors love the island"
    words:
      - nautae
      - amant
      - insulam
      - rēgīnam
      - turba
    answer:
      - nautae
      - insulam
      - amant

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The queen sees the crowd"
    words:
      - rēgīna
      - videt
      - turbam
      - umbra
      - ambulant
    answer:
      - rēgīna
      - turbam
      - videt

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The woman prepares the dinner"
    words:
      - fēmina
      - parat
      - cēnam
      - glōria
      - amat
    answer:
      - fēmina
      - cēnam
      - parat

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The girls carry water to the table"
    words:
      - puellae
      - portant
      - aquam
      - ad
      - mēnsam
      - pugnant
    answer:
      - puellae
      - aquam
      - ad
      - mēnsam
      - portant

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The farmer walks to the gate"
    words:
      - agricola
      - ambulat
      - ad
      - portam
      - nāvigat
    answer:
      - agricola
      - ad
      - portam
      - ambulat

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The women see the shadows"
    words:
      - fēminae
      - umbrās
      - vident
      - glōriae
      - portant
    answer:
      - fēminae
      - umbrās
      - vident

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The girl walks with the sailor"
    words:
      - puella
      - ambulat
      - cum
      - nautā
      - patria
    answer:
      - puella
      - cum
      - nautā
      - ambulat

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The letters please the queen"
    words:
      - epistulae
      - placent
      - rēgīnae
      - fābula
      - puellīs
    answer:
      - epistulae
      - rēgīnae
      - placent

  - type: sentence
    prompt: "The shadow enters the house"
    words:
      - umbra
      - intrat
      - domum
      - cēna
      - clamat
    answer:
      - umbra
      - domum
      - intrat
---

```